

### Suhail Karbhari

Senior Sales & Biz Dev Leader

+966 55 287 8815

karbharisuhail@gmail.com

http://linkedin.com/in/suhail1985

Dammam, Saudi Arabia

With 16+ years of experience in Sales & Business Development of Multi Cloud, Cyber Security & SaaS Solutions, I have successfully managed to outgrow the business to multi-million dollars with consistent growth rate of 20% YoY. I have been a Product Owner for 3 SaaS applications and leading a team of 15 members.

| Sales Planning | Key Account Mgmt | Negotiation |
|----------------|------------------|-------------|
| P&L Analysis   | Team Mgmt        | CRM/ERP     |

### **EDUCATION**

### MBA in Information Technology

National Institute of Management

### Marketing Strategy Certificate

Cornell University

### **CERTIFICATION**

### **Microsoft Cloud**

Microsoft Certified Technology Specialist Microsoft Sales & Presales Specialist Microsoft Virtual Academy – Gold Badge

### Alibaba Cloud

Accredited Cloud Associate

#### **Google Cloud**

Google Cloud Sales Expert

### **AWS Cloud**

**Business Professional** 

Certificate in Executive Leadership & Virtual Selling
Certificate in Artificial Intelligence & Digital Twin

### **EXPERIENCE**

### 2015 – Present Position Reporting to Reported by Achievements

### Squid Technologies Co. Head of Sales & Biz Development Group President & CEO 15 Team Member

- Grown business to \$3.2 Million.
- Achieved 200+ active customer.
- Product owner for 3 SaaS products

### Responsibilities

- Developing strategic business plans to achieve company Vision & Goals.
- Manage Key Accounts, Vendors, Distributor & Alliance Partners.
- Preparing Sales, P&L and Performance Reports to help top management.

### 2012 – 2015 Position Reporting to Reported by Achievements

## Alfalak Electronics Co. Division Manager – Cloud Computing General Manager 15 Team Member

- 200+ partners/resellers recruited.
- 2 strategic government initiatives.
- Sales of up to \$ 1 million.

### Responsibilities

- To manage and lead all the 15-channel sales executive in three major territories of KSA.
- Develop Product Plan including Sales
   & Marketing for Cloud Computing products.
- Recruitment & Enablement of Channel Partners for indirect sales.

# 2009 - 2012 Position Reporting to Reported by Achievements

### **EXA Information Technology Product & Partner Dev Manager CEO**

#### 3 Team members

- 20+ partners recruited.
- Executed GTM/Branding campaign.
- Sales of up to \$ 100 K.

### 2008 – 2009 Position Reporting to Reported by Achievements

### Alsayed Group of Companies ERP Functional Consultant Reporting to Deputy CEO

Reported by 2 Team Members

- Successfully implemented the ERP system.
- Developed group wise IT strategy and development plan